scansoft.com 2017-03-20

# Privacy Policies | Nuance

### Nuance Communications, Inc. Privacy Policy  
General information

Nuance Communications, Inc. and its subsidiaries ("Nuance") provides this Privacy Policy ( "Privacy Policy") to help you understand how we collect, use and disclose information, including personal information that you may provide to us or that we may obtain as our products and services are used. We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time, so please check back with us periodically. This Privacy Policy applies to www.nuance.com ("Website") and to certain Nuance products, and services, including those for consumer use ("Nuance Products"). This Privacy Policy explains Nuance's information practices including:

  * How Nuance uses the personal information you share with us and that we learn about you because of our relationship.
  * What personal information, if any, Nuance may share about you and the conditions we use to protect your information if it must be shared.
  * Other things you should know about privacy and Nuance.

"Personal Information" includes information that alone or when in combination with other information may be used to readily identify, contact, or locate you or a specific individual.

### Collected information and usage

By using the Website or Nuance Products, you consent to the collection and use of your Personal Information by Nuance consistent with applicable data protection law and this Privacy Policy which is expressly incorporated into any applicable Website or Nuance Product Terms of Use or End-User License Agreement.  You also represent to us that you have any and all authorizations necessary to use these Nuance Products including using them to process Personal Information. Nuance collects and uses the information you provide to us, including information obtained from your use of this Website or a Nuance Product. We may use or share Personal Information (e.g., name, address, telephone number, email address, and location) where it is necessary for us to complete a transaction or do something that you have asked us to do. Also, we may use the information that we collect for our internal purposes to develop, tune, enhance, and improve our products and services, and for advertising and marketing consistent with this Privacy Policy. By using Nuance products and services, you acknowledge, consent and agree that Nuance may collect, process, and use the information that you provide to us and that such information shall only be used by Nuance or third parties acting under the direction of Nuance, pursuant to confidentiality agreements, to develop, tune, enhance, and improve Nuance services and products. Nuance will not use the contents of any communications provided to us through your use of Nuance Products for any purpose except as set forth above. Nuance collects and uses information from you in several ways:

**Website or Nuance Product Usage.** Nuance (or Nuance vendors and suppliers) may observe your activities, preferences, and transactional data (such as your IP address and browser type) as well as related usage behavior depending on whether you are using our Website or a particular Nuance Product. We may use this data for any purpose unless we tell you otherwise in connection with a particular Website or product. While we may collect or log this information, we do not identify you or match this non-Personal Information with your other Personal Information unless or except if we believe doing so will help us better respond to a request you have made. Where such non-Personal Information is linked to your Personal Information we will treat such information as Personal Information. For clarity, when we refer to usage of Website or Nuance Product Usage Data in this section, we do not mean the contents of your voice data or text and related data derived from the contents of your communications using Nuance Products. For information about specific Nuance Products, please see specific privacy notices directed to such products.

**Nuance Product Usage.** Certain Nuance Products require you to enter Speech Data in order to use and derive the benefits of the particular product. These Nuance Products collect and process the Speech Data you input into the Nuance Products. Nuance or third parties acting under the direction of Nuance, pursuant to confidentiality agreements, use the Speech Data to develop, tune, enhance, and improve Nuance services and products. Nuance will not use the contents of any Speech Data provided to us through your use of Nuance Products for any purpose except as set forth above. "Speech Data" means the audio files, associated text and transcriptions and log files provided by you hereunder or generated in connection with Nuance Products. Speech Data may include Personal Information.

**E-Commerce.** You may be asked to share Personal Information such as your name, address, telephone number, and email address when you make purchases, seek customer or technical support or otherwise interact with Nuance. When you shop online or buy direct from Nuance, these purchase transactions may be conducted through Nuance vendors and suppliers. Vendors and suppliers engaged by Nuance on behalf of Nuance may have their use of your Personal Information limited by this Privacy Policy, contractual restrictions, and applicable law. Nuance (through its vendors or suppliers) may limit the acceptance of orders to particular jurisdictions and as permitted by applicable law. You may also make purchases of Nuance Products; seek customer or technical support through Nuance's distributors or service providers. In these circumstances, the collection of your Personal Information may occur directly by the distributor or service provider or a third-party partner on their website, which will state the privacy policy or policies governing the collection of such information.

**Product Registration & Technical Support. **Nuance may allow customers to register products online or through similar ways. Personal Information or data provided for such purposes may be used to carry out the request, service, or agreement for which the information is submitted. With your consent, we may also use the information you provide in online registration forms to notify you periodically about important changes to the Website or Application (such as a change to this Privacy Policy or notice of a security breach), new Nuance products and services, and special offers and promotions that may be of interest to you. If you register, we may ask for, among other things, your name, address, email, telephone number, type of product purchased, or other product-identifying information.

_Failure to register any Nuance product will not diminish the rights you have under the applicable product warranty._

**Online Promotions, Contests and Sweepstakes.** You may be asked to provide an email address or screen name, or other Personal Information, for entry into a particular promotion, including sweepstakes and contests, so that we can let you know if you won a prize. The specific rules and regulations governing the particular promotion, contest or sweepstakes will vary and your participation constitutes your agreement to abide by those rules and regulations. Certain promotions, contests or sweepstakes may be run by a Nuance service provider or vendor or co-branded with one of our partners. In these instances the collection of your Personal Information may occur directly by the service provider or vendor or a third-party partner on their website. The promotion will state the privacy policy or policies governing the collection of such information if they should differ from this Privacy Policy.

**Children.** The Nuance Website and Nuance Consumer Products are not directed at children. If you are under 18 or otherwise would be required to have parent or guardian consent to share information with Nuance, you should not send any information about yourself to us. As required by law, if a person under 13 submits information through any part of a Nuance Website or a Nuance Product, and we learn the person submitting the information is such a child, we will attempt to delete this information as soon as possible.

### When Nuance may share collected information

As mentioned in the beginning of this Privacy Policy, Nuance may share Personal Information within Nuance to fulfill its obligations to you and operate its business consistent with this Privacy Policy and applicable data protection law. In addition to what is expressly stated in this Privacy Policy, we may also share your Personal Information with third parties in the following situations:

**Nuance Affiliates, Vendors and Suppliers.** Nuance works with many affiliated third parties, vendors, distributors, and suppliers. To the extent it is necessary for these groups to provide their products and services to us and provide products and services you have requested, these third parties may have access to or process your Personal Information. Nuance may also sometimes permit our authorized service providers to have access to aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, and related Website or Application information. These transfers of aggregate statistics do not involve Personal Information or data.

**Recruitment and Job Applications**. Residents of the United States may provide us with Personal Information through our Website. Personal information such as that contained on a resume or curriculum vitae may be submitted in connection with a job application or inquiry. We may use this information throughout Nuance (worldwide) for the purpose of employment consideration or your inquiry. We may keep your information on file for future consideration.

**Enabling Services.** Nuance offers a variety of services and functions through its Websites ("Nuance Services"). Personal Information that is collected through a Website may be used and/or disclosed to third parties in order to enable us to provide Nuance Services. For example, the Nuance Website may allow you to interface with a third party website or application. To facilitate that connection, we may use your Personal Information and/or disclose your Personal Information to third parties.

**Public Areas**. Any information disclosed in public areas of a Nuance Website or to the extent possible in a Nuance Product or other website (Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, etc.) will become public information. We cannot control the use of information disclosed in public forums, such as forums, bulletin boards, blogs, chat rooms, and networking functions of mobile-device applications. You should exercise caution when disclosing information in these public areas, and be careful how you disclose your Personal Information. Content posted in public areas of the Nuance Website or Nuance Products, including advice and opinions, represent the views and is the responsibility of those who post the content. Nuance does not necessarily endorse, support, verify, or agree with the content posted.

**Mergers, Acquisitions, and Insolvency.** If Nuance should ever file for bankruptcy or merge with another company, or if Nuance should decide to buy, sell, or reorganize some part or all of its business, Nuance may be required to disclose your Personal Information and Speech Data to prospective or actual purchasers in connection with one of these transactions

 **As Required by Law and Other Extraordinary Disclosures**. Nuance may be required to disclose your Personal Information and Speech Data if it: (i) believes it is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process (such as a court order, subpoena, search warrant, etc.) or other legal requirements of any governmental authority, (ii) would potentially mitigate our liability in an actual or potential lawsuit, (iii) is otherwise necessary to protect our rights or property, or (iv) is necessary to protect the legal rights or property of others.

### Security

If Nuance learns of a security system's breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using this Website or a Nuance Product or providing Personal Information to us, you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues relating to your use of this Website or Nuance Product. Nuance may post a notice on this Website if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser or mobile device enabling you to view the Nuance Website or Application. Nuance may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances or communicate with you by other means if we can. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing.

### Links to third-party websites and co-branded websites

This Website or Nuance Product may contain links to third-party websites, however, please be aware that Nuance is not responsible for and cannot control the privacy practices of these other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy policies for these other websites, as they may differ from ours. This Website or Nuance Product also contains links to co-branded websites that may display Nuance's logo and trademarks but which are maintained by third parties. Such websites may be identified by the fact that they do not display a "Nuance.com" URL. Please read the privacy policy on the co-branded website for the applicable privacy practices relating to personal information collected via that website, as it may differ from this Privacy Policy.

**This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by Nuance on its Website or through Nuance Products.**

### Special notice to international visitors and customers

Because Nuance operates globally, we may transfer your Personal Information and Speech Data within our global operations to fulfill our obligations to you, but always subject to the limitations of applicable data protection law and this Privacy Policy. Privacy laws differ across the globe. To help visitors whose native language may not be English understand our privacy practices, we may provide special information on our Privacy Policies that may be applicable to these visitors in different languages. Nuance entities outside the United States may have supplemental privacy policies that may apply in those countries.

If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, including those whose privacy laws may be more strict than U.S. law, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States to Nuance. By providing your personal data you consent to that transfer and processing.

### Marketing communications

When you provide Nuance with Personal Information, we may communicate with you using the information you have given us to provide you with information we think may be of interest to you.

### Your California Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, permits California residents to request and obtain from us a list of what personal information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year and the names and addresses of those third parties. Requests may be made only once a year and are free of charge. Under Section 1798.83, we currently do not share any personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. You may choose to opt-out of the sharing of your personal information with third parties for marketing purposes at any time by submitting a request in writing to Legal Dept.—Privacy, One Wayside Road, Burlington, MA 01803 or by emailing us at [privacy@nuance.com](mailto:privacy@nuance.com). It is important to note that this opt-out does not prohibit disclosures made for non-marketing purposes or for purposes of assisting us with our own marketing. 

### Cookies

Nuance uses "cookies" to help personalize your use of our site, including for storing user preferences, such as your language preference. A cookie is a text file stored on your computer. Cookies store bits of information that we use to help make our site work. They can't run any code and don’t contain viruses. No one can read our cookies except us. 

**Information About Cookies.** A cookie is a text file stored on your computer. Cookies store bits of information that we use to help make our site work. They can’t run any code and don’t contain viruses. No one can read our cookies except us.

**How We Use Cookies.** Nuance uses cookies to improve your experience on this site; some are essential to the proper function of this site. We also use cookies to help us understand how people use our site and to serve Nuance ads when you visit other sites.

**Types of Cookies We Use**

  * Security: These cookies allow us to secure access to your account
  * Preference: These cookies are used to store your preferences like language choice and display of job search results
  * Analytics: We track site traffic patterns so we can identify popular site content and potential site problems
  * Advertising: We use non-identifiable information about you to show you advertising on our site

**Your Choices Regarding Cookies.** You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being set, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you clear your cookies, you will need to opt out again. If you use a different computer or browser, your choices will not be carried over.

Nuance adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising from the Digital Advertising Alliance. You can opt out of targeted advertising by third parties by setting your browser to decline third party cookies. You can also delete the advertiser’s cookie each time. Many of the third parties are members of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). You can opt-out of targeted advertising by all NAI members by visiting the NAI site.

### Enforcement and more information

Nuance has self-certified that it complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Nuance has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, please visit: <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. On October 6, 2015, the European Court of Justice issued a judgment that declared invalid the European Commission’s Decision 2000/520/EC of 26 July 2000 “on the adequacy of the protection provided by the safe harbour privacy principles,” (“Safe Harbor”). Safe Harbor is a legal mechanism to permit transfers of EU residents’ personal information to the United States and to ensure that the information is legally protected at a level that is considered adequate by EU standards. Since the judgment was issued, the EU and US have been in negotiations to determine a path forward for Safe Harbor and it is expected that information will not be available until the end of January 2016. Nuance Communications, Inc. has self-certified to the Safe Harbor principles in the past, but in light of the recent judgment, has executed ‘standard contractual clauses’ with its EU subsidiaries who collect and export personal information in order to allow transfers and the continued protection of EU residents’ data during the interim period while we await further guidance from the European Commission. If you would like to contact us directly about the Safe Harbor program, please contact us at [privacy@nuance.com](mailto:privacy@nuance.com). For individuals outside the European Economic Area, Nuance endeavors to comply with applicable law for the international transfer of your personal information. When Nuance receives formal written complaints related to personal information and privacy matters, it is Nuance's policy to contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. We will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of personal data that cannot be resolved between Nuance and an individual.

### Changes to this privacy policy by Nuance

If in the future we change our Privacy Policy, we will post the new Privacy Policy on this Website or Application. We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy in the future. Your continued use of this Website or Nuance Product following a change in the Privacy Policy represents consent to the new Privacy Policy to the fullest extent permitted by law. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy.

### Contacting Nuance

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please email us at [privacy@nuance.com](mailto:privacy@nuance.com) or write to us at:

**Nuance Communications  
One Wayside Road**  
**Burlington, MA, 01748  
USA  
Attention:  Legal Department- Privacy**

Updated: December 2015
